So, in this video,
在此视频中
I'll be showing you how to use transfer learning to train a network
我将演示如何使用迁移学习
that can properly classify those images of cats and dogs.
训练网络正确地分类猫的图像和狗的图像
What we'll do here is use a pre-trained network to
我们将使用预先训练的网络
actually detect and extract features from the images.
检测和提取图像中的特征
This is really good for solving
这种方法非常适合解决
many challenging problems in computer vision and other fields.
计算机视觉和很多其他领域的挑战性难题
So, specifically, these networks have been trained on the ImageNet dataset,
具体而言 这些网络用 ImageNet 数据集进行了训练
this is a giant dataset with
ImageNet 是一个庞大的数据集
over a million labeled images and a thousand different categories.
有 100 万个有标签图像和 1000 个不同的类别
These networks use an architecture called convolutional layers that exploit
这些网络使用一种叫做卷积层的结构
patterns and structure that we see in images and learn from that.
并从在图像中看到的模式和结构中学习规律
These networks have dozens or even hundreds of different convolutional layers.
这些网络包含几十个甚至几百个不同的卷积层
They are extremely deep compared to what you've seen so far.
与你到目前为止见过的网络相比 深度极高
This combination of a massive dataset with
庞大的数据集和庞大的神经网络相结合
a massive neural network is come to be known as deep learning.
称为深度学习
What's really cool is that once these networks are trained on ImageNet,
真正酷的是 用 ImageNet 训练这些网络后
the models work amazingly well as feature detectors on images that aren't in ImageNet.
这些模型作为特征检测器 在不是 ImageNet 的图像上效果也非常棒
So, you can, for instance,
例如
apply these networks to images of these cats and dogs and actually extract the features.
你可以将这些网络应用到猫和狗的图像上 并提取出特征
Then you use those features as inputs to a new classifier which you can
然后使用这些特征作为新分类器的输入
train to accurately classify your cat and dog photos.
并训练该分类器正确地对猫的照片和狗的照片分类
You can download these pre-trained networks using torchvision.models.
你可以使用 torchvision.models 下载这些预先训练的网络
So, we're going to include that in our imports.
导入该模块
Otherwise is pretty much what you've seen before.
其他的和之前看到的差不多
Now we have our models.
现在有模型了
Most of these models from towards vision and also other deep learning frameworks
来自 torchvision 和 Keras 等其他深度学习框架的模型
like Cara's require these images to be 224 by 224.
要求图像大小是 224 x 224
So, these are the size of the images that the networks should train on originally.
网络一开始训练时就使用这些大小的图像
You'll also need to measure the normalization that was used when the models were trained.
还需要和训练模型时使用的标准化方法保持一致
These colored channels were normalized separately,
这些颜色通道是单独标准化的
so the red green and blue and the means for each of these channels
即红绿蓝通道 这里列出了每个通道的均值
are listed here as their standard deviations are listed here.
这里列出了标准差
So, I'll let you actually define the trained transforms.
你将需要定义训练转换
So, the transforms for
需要对训练数据进行转换
the training data and the transforms for the test and validation data.
并对测试和验证数据进行转换 00:02:22,314 --&gt; 00:02:26,800 像之前我演示的那样构建转换
that you need to make the images 224 by 224,
需要注意的是 图像必须是 224 x 224
you need to normalize them with these means and
需要用这些均值和标准差
these standard deviations and you'd probably
标准化这些图像
want to use data augmentation on the training images.
可能需要对训练图像进行数据增强
As an example of transfer learning,
作为迁移学习的示例
I'm going show you how to do this with a model called DenseNet.
我将演示如何使用这个叫做 DenseNet 的模型完成这些步骤
So, we can load the model like so.
加载模型
So, model equals models.densenet.
输入 model = models.densenet
So, there's a few and typically this number
有多个模型
afterwards tells you how many layers are in the network.
结尾的数字表示网络中有多少层级
So, in general, more layers means it's going to have better accuracy,
通常 层级越多 准确率越高
it will just get this 121,
我们选择 121 这个模型
we don't need crazy accuracy right now.
暂时不需要太高的准确率
So, you want say pre-trained equals true and so this will
输入 pretrained=True
download the model to your computer if you don't already have it.
如果计算机上没有该模型的话 系统将下载到计算机上
So, we can look at the architecture.
看看架构
So, here we see this DenseNet architecture has a part
可以看出这个 DenseNet 架构有个叫特征的部分
called features that is built up of all these convolutional layers.
由这些卷积层组成
As you scroll down very far because this is a very deep network, keep going, keep going,
一直往下滚动 因为这是个非常深的网络 继续滚动
at the end we see apart called classifier
在最后 看到叫做分类器的部分
which is just one linear transformation at the end as taking
它是在末尾的一个线性转换
the features from the feature part and passing them to 1,000 output units.
将特征部分的特征传入 1,000 个输出单元中
So, transfer learning the features part like all these layers up
对于迁移学习来说 特征部分
here above here work really well with other datasets.
即所有这些层级在其他数据集上的效果很棒
However, this classifier has a thousand outputs.
但是 这个分类器有 1000 个输出
So, this has been trained particularly like specifically for the ImageNet dataset.
它是专门针对 ImageNet 数据集进行训练的
So, this part we're going to want to replace it
我们需要将这部分替换为
with a new classifier that has built for our dataset.
专门为我们的数据集构建的新分类器
Then we will train this classifier on our dataset and
我们将用我们的数据集训练此分类器
just use the features that come into here as the input for this classifier.
使用这里的特征作为此分类器的输入
So, the first thing we want to do is actually freeze
首先 我们需要冻结
the parameters in the features section of DenseNet.
DenseNet 特征部分的参数
So, we don't want to train or otherwise
我们不想训练或计算
calculate the gradients for that part because we just
此部分的梯度
want to keep it static and just use it as a feature detector.
因为我们只希望使其保持静态 用作特征检测器
So, you can basically do for param and model.parameters.
输入 for param in model.parameters()
So, this is going to go through all the parameters in a model and then we can
这样会检查模型中的所有参数
say requires grad equals false.
然后输入 param.requires_grad = False
So, this will shut off gradients like calculating gradients for other parameters in
这样将关闭模型中的所有参数 不计算梯度
the model and we won't train them when we do the training steps.
在训练步骤不会训练这些梯度
Now, we're just going to define our classifier.
现在定义分类器
So, this is similarly to what we built before where
和之前的操作相似
you can just build a classifier as a sequential model.
构建一个序列模型分类器
So, I'm just using an order dict here to get
在这里使用有序字典
our first linear transformation into
将第一个线性转换传入 ReLu 中
a revenue into another linear transformation for our output.
再传入另一个线性转换里 获得输出
So, we have two outputs here and one for cat and one for dog.
这里有两个输出 一个是猫的图像 一个是狗的图像
The input features here for this classifier are coming from here.
这个分类器的输入特征来自这里
So, we can see that this classifier,
对于这个分类器
the input features are 1,024.
输入特征是 1,024 个
So, that means that the feature section of this network,
表明这个网络的特征部分
the output of that is 1,024 values.
输出是 1,024 个值
So, we want to use that as the input for
我们想使用这些值作为分类器的输入
a classifier and so we have 1,024 values here as well.
因此这里也是 1,024 个值
So, in general, you're going to need to match up the size of
总之 特征部分的输出大小
the output from the features part with the input of your classifier.
需要跟分类器的输入大小保持一致
Now that we have our classifier defined,
定义好分类器后
we just need to replace the DenseNet classifier with our classifier.
我们需要将 DenseNet 分类器替换为我们的分类器
Now, this network is ready to be trained.
现在 这个网络可以训练了
The problem though is that now we're using a really deep neural network.
但是问题是 现在这个神经网络深度非常高
So, like I said before this DenseNet has 121 different layers.
就像之前说的 这个 DenseNet 有 121 个不同的层级
So, if you're going try to train this on a CPU like we had before,
如果要像之前一样 尝试在 CPU 上训练
it's going to take a very long time.
训练时间会非常长
So, instead, we're going to use the GPU to do the calculations.
因此 我们将使用 GPU 进行计算
Using the GPU you can get speedups of like 100 times,
使用 GPU 后速度可以提升 100 倍或 500 倍
500 times, it's pretty crazy.
非常惊人
PyTorch like pretty much all the other frameworks uses library called
和几乎所有其他框架一样
CUDA to actually run our networks on the GPU.
PyTorch 使用库 CUDA 在 GPU 上运行网络
So, if you're wondering more about CUDA it's all here.
如果你要深入了解 CUDA 请参阅此处
CUDA is a software library that runs on NVIDIA GPUs and it uses
CUDA 是一个在 NVIDIA GPU 上运行的软件库
these GPUs to efficiently compute linear algebra computations.
它使用这些 GPU 高效地进行线性代数计算
So, remember that a lot of the stuff and deep learning networks is
注意 深度学习网络中的很多运算
basically just linear algebra matrix multiplications and that sort of thing.
其实就是线性代数矩阵乘法
These computations can be done really fast on a GPU using CUDA.
使用 CUDA 在 GPU 上可以飞快地执行这些计算
So, the idea with PyTorch is that we move
对于 PyTorch 来说
our model parameters and other tensors to the GPU using something
我们使用 model.to('cuda') 将模型参数和其他张量移到 GPU 上
like model.to(cuda) and we can move them back from the GPU to the CPU with model.to(CPU).
然后使用 model.to('CPU') 将它们移回 CPU 上
So, I'm going to demonstrate how fast this actually goes by
我将演示下速度如何
comparing how long it takes to do a forward and backward pass with and without a GPU.
比较下使用 GPU 进行前向传播和反向传播的速度及不使用 GPU 的速度
So, here is fairly normal training pass that you've seen
这是一个正常的训练传播 之前见过
before just to find my criterion to find my optimizer.
定义 criterion 和优化器
But now, remember that we don't want to
注意 我们不想训练特征部分
train the features part but we just want to train the classifier part.
只想训练分类器部分
So, in optimizer I'm passing in model.classifier.parameters.
在优化器中 传入 model.classifier.parameters
Here I'm looping through using a device CPU and
使用 CPU 和 CUDA 进行循环
CUDA and to get our model to whatever device we're using you
将模型转到要使用的设备上
say model.to(device) and as usual we're getting
输入 model.to(device)
our images and our labels from the training loader and to use CUDA,
正常地从训练加载器获取图像和标签
to use GPU needs to move them to CUDA or wherever.
要使用 CUDA 要使用 GPU 需要将它们移到 CUDA 上
So, inputs.to(device), labels.to(device).
输入 inputs.to(device) labels.to(device)
So, when a device is CPU,
当设备是 CPU 时
it'll move them to the CPU.
会将它们移到 CPU 上
When a device is CUDA,
当设备是 CUDA 时
it'll move them to our GPU.
会将它们移到 GPU 上
Otherwise, it's basically all you need to do to change
这些就是让网络在 GPU 上运行
your code for your networks to run on a GPU.
要更改的所有代码
So, we can see comparing writing this code on a CPU verse GPU,
比较在 CPU 上和在 GPU 上的速度
that we get a huge time-saver.
可以看出节省了大量时间
So, for one batch it takes over five seconds on the CPU but nine milliseconds.
对于一个批次来说 在 CPU 上需要用时 5 秒以上 在 GPU 上只需 9 毫秒
So, this is just a massive improvement.
改进了很多
We can write device agnostic code which will
我们可以编写设备不可知代码
automatically use CUDA if it's available on your machine.
如果机器上有 CUDA 则会自动使用 CUDA
It's basically you just do torch.device is CUDA if CUDA is just
输入 torch.device 如果 CUDA 可用 则使用 CUDA
available and then otherwise use the CPU and this becomes this device variable.
否则使用 CPU 这个变成 device 变量
So, then anytime you have a tensor or a model,
每次使用张量或模型时
you just say tensor.to(device) or model.to(device).
直接输入 tensor.to(device) 或 model.to(device)
If it's already on the CPU,
如果已经在 CPU 上
then it'll just stay on the CPU.
在保留不动
If it's ready on the GPU it'll stay there but if it's not,
如果已经在 GPU 上 则保留不动
it'll move to the appropriate one.
如果不在的话 则移到相应的设备上
From here I'm going to let you finish training the model and pretty much
从现在开始 将由你来完成模型训练
everything is exactly the same except that you're only training,
流程几乎不变 但是现在仅训练
the classifier which you've defined like
在这里定义的分类器
this and you're using the GPU now. All right. Good luck.
并且使用 GPU 加油